Guide to the Harwood Family Papers, 1722-1962
Department of Special Collections
- Autographs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 7. Thomas Truxton autograph salutation & sig. & engrvd. pic. of medal.
  - 8. Edward Preble Autograph, engraved portrait & pic. of medal
  - 9. Stephen Decatur auto. engrvd portrait, & sig. of James [Barron]
  - 10. David Porter auto. & salutation, engrvd portrait
  - 11. James Lawrence auto, engrvd portrait, typed biog. sketch verso ptd. map Battle of Lake Erie 9/10, 1813
  - 12. O.H. Perry auto. Aug. 11, 1815 &engraved portrait
  - 13. Thomas Macdonough sal. A. & engraved portrait
  - 14. Joseph Story sal. A. & engraved portrait
  - 15. Henry Middleton A & typed biog. sketch
  - 16. Daniel D. Tompkins A & sal. & sig.
  - 17. J. J. Nicholson A. 2 Aug. 1824
  - 18. Andrew A. Harwood sig. & photo & sig. & sal. of E.A. DeVallette
  - 19. Basil Hall sig.
  - 20. Edward Livingston sal., sig., engraved portrait, typed biog.
  - 21. William John Duane A. sentiment S.
  - 22. George Cruikshank 1837autograph on a title page & an illus. by G.C. of Robinson Crusoe
  - 23. R.B. Hayes sig. on card 18__
  - 24. D. Duane sig. [sister of E.F. Bache]
  - 25. Gertrude Atherton ALS n.d.to _____? #84
  - 26. Nancy Astor sig. (Vicountess) & clip
  - 27. Archibald MacLeish sig. on title page of ptd. addre
  - 28. cvr. for A. Lincoln doc.
  - 29. Robert A. Millikan - A.
  - 30. Gertrude Atherton - A.
  - 31. Joseph H. Choate ALS to E. Denman McNear 11Jan, 1916 re: Alpha Delta Phi
  - 32. Wm. S. Sims A. Newport, R.I. June, 1923
  - 33. Richard Halliburton A. & sentiment to Wilson Harwood
  - 34. Gertrude Atherton 1931A. on Hamlin School p.c.
  - 35. J. _____ Esq. (32) A.
  - 36. Frances Hodgson Burnett A. 1/92
  - 37. Chs. C. Turner A.
  - 38. Fedrika Bremer Auto.
  - 39. _____lina de Murskc_____ A.
  - 40. C.W. Cadman A.
  - 41. Louis Adamic A. 1940
  - 42. Chas. Gordon A.
  - 43. Geo. W. _____ A. (27)
  - 44. T. Vaughan SR A. on Regent's Park admission ticket.
  - 45. Algernon S. Sullivan to Margaret ANS
  - 46. J.A. Garfield autograph
  - 47. Calvin Coolidge A. on White House card
  - 48. Fanny Janauschek A. San Francisco June, 1865
  - 49. B. M. Boyer M.C. A. & photo
  - 50. Alexander V. Griswold A. & facs., engraved portrai
  - 51. Frances Hodgson Burnett [facs.?] AQS from Little Lord Fauntleroy n.d.
  - 52. Franklin Harwood calling card sig.
  - 53. Woodrow Wilson Autograph
  - 54. Napoleon III, imperial cover to Murat
  - 55. _____Exec. Mansion cvr. to Miss Harwood (28)
  - 56. A.D_____ sig. to Lt. Andrew A. Harwood Legation at Naples
  - 57. Lt. Gen. Bernard ptd. calling card
  - 58. G.B_____ Autograph San Francisco June 10, 1878
  - 59. Vivian Burnett A. & quote
  - 60. Dept. of State cvr. 1894to G.S. Wilson
  - 61. Henry M. Stanley A. -?facs.
  - 62. Horatio Alger, Jr. A.
  - 63. E. Sothern (actor) A.
  - 64. H. J. Montague A. & typed biog. note
  - 65. W. M. Crane A. & photo (naval officer)
  - 66. Dion Boncica[net] or [relt]? Irish actor A. & typed biog. note
  - 67. [David] KalaKaua A. & typed biog. note
  - 68. T. Adolphus _____ A. & sal.
  - 69. U.S. Grant A.
  - 70. Grover Cleveland A. Feb. 21, 1887 &Frances Folsom Cleveland A. Feb. 15, 1887.
  - 71. Mahlon Dickerson A.
  - 72. L. L. Lomax A. & typed biog. note
  - 73. Louis M. Goldsborough A. & photo & typed biog.note
  - 74. A. H. Foote 2 A. photo
  - 75. S. F. DuPont 2 autographs A.date 1/1/1863photo
  - 76. W.T. Sherman autograph, typed biog. note, engrvd portrait
  - 77. Hugh McCulloch autograph, typed biog. note
  - 78. R.W. Gilder Auto. (check Endorsement)
  - 79. E. Everett A. typed biog. note, engrvd portrait
  - 80. A.D. Bache A., typed biog. note
  - 81. M.C. Perry A. etc.
  - 82. C.G. [Perry] A.
  - 83. [Catalyna?] [Totten?] A.
  - 84. Major Sabine [A.]?
  - 85. Charles Danberry A., typed biog. note
  - 86. Tho. Sergeant 2 A. & typed biog. note
  - 87. [John] Phillips AN frag., typed biog. note.
  - 88. John G. Whittier A. & addressed to Grosvenor M. Robinson Apr. 1, 1882
  - 89. I. H. Hill A., typed biog. note
  - 90. R.W. Emerson A. & mag. photo
  - 91. R. J. Walker A. (frank) mag. photo, verso unidentified engraved portrait
  - 92. H. Clay A., engraved portrait, verso - engraved portrait of Calhoun
  - 93. H. M. Kilgore ANS n.d.
  - 94. V. B[ush] ANS n.d.
  - 95. [C. Lion; or C. Iren; or Cyrus W_____]? cvr. addressed to Harwood & _____
  - 96. _____ cvr. addressed to Harwood
  - 97. Marie Carie, photograph
  - 98. Casper Nista engraved portrait and photograph
  - 99. Thomas Jefferson, on engrave
  - Letter Book, May 24, 1803.Copies of letters sent by John E. Harwood and poems by John E. Harwood., 1 vol. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Inspection Book, Ordnance. Book maintained by Powell at the Washington Navy Yard, 1846-., 1 vol. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Some tipped in letters.
  - General-Orders. General orders inscribed in long hand, probably by Stephen B. Luce., 1 vol. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - A.A. Harwood's log on the U.S. Frigate Constitution, 1826,1 vol. (Vol. 2nd) (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Framed Items and Oversize
  - 1. 1722, May 8,Land Patent George I of Eng. to John Depuy land in Orange Co. N.Y. (2000 acres) s. [W.] Babin, SEC On verso 2 ads repts s. Arch d. Kennedy to John Depuy, 7/19, 1727, and Sept. 15, 1736,Rept. ADS [?] deputy recr. gen. to Mrs. Anne Depuy June 28, 1746,to Thomas Preston Sept. 11, 1756.Sig. of Gilliland and This belongs to Joseph M. _____ 1795/. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 2. 1758, May 8.Endenture - land in Orange Co. N.Y. Francis Many and wife Margaret of Philadelphia, to Thomas Preston of Philadelphia. s. Francis Many, Margaret Many, John David, Jno. Reily, John Kirke. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 3. 1764, Jan. 7.Indenture for land in Orange Co. N.Y. John Peter [Tetard] and wife Frances and William Gilliland s. J.S. Tetard, Fr. Tetard, Robert [Pillson], and W. Cunningham, William Smith (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - 4. [Boston Newspaper] 1 sheet ptd. by Green and Russell July 1766 (Othertype 26)
  - 5. Society of the Cincinnati Membership Cert. for Samuel Snow Esqr. Jan. 1, 1784s. Geo. Washington same as above for Benjamin Franklin July 1789s. & Washington (Othertype 1)
  - [UNK] (Othertype 2)
  - 6. Newport Marine Soc. cert. membership of Peleg Wood Jan. 7, 1794s. Benjamin Sayer and Jenkin G. Warner 7/25/73 (Othertype 3)
  - 7. General Advertiser (Philadelphia) Mon. Dec. 22, 1794 Pub.by Benjamin Franklin Bache (Othertype 24)
  - 8. The Newport (Rhode Island) Mercury Publisher- Henry Barber Tues. April 26, 1796 (Othertype 28)
  - 9. The Newport Mercury Tues. May 2, 1797 (Othertype 29)
  - 10. The Newport Mercury Tues. Aug. 29, 1797 (Othertype 30)
  - 11. Michigan Essays; or The Impartial Observer (Detroit) Vol. 1, No. 1 Thurs. Aug. 31, 1809.Ptd. and Pub. by James M. Miller (Othertype 31)
  - 12. A.A. Harwood Appointment as midshipman Jan. 1, 1818s. James Monroe, Wm. Blagrove, P.W. [Crowninshield] framed - on top (Othertype 4)
  - A.A. Harwood appointment Lieutenant Feb. 21, 1828s. J.Q. Adams, Saml. L. Southard, R.B. [Maury] (Othertype 5)
  - 13. Paris - ptd. map 1837Leclere (Othertype 34)
  - Rhode Island Historical Society member certificate A.A. Harwood, July 5, 1841John Howland, [W.R.?] Staples. (Othertype 6)
  - 14. A.A. Harwood appointment Commander Oct. 4, 1848s. James K. Polk, J. Y. Mason, L.B. Hardin (Othertype 7)
  - 15. Andrew A Harwood appointment Commander Feb. 9, 1849s. James K. Polk, J.Y. Mason, L.B. Hardin (Othertype 8)
  - Alfred Wheeler appointment U.S. Attorney General for Southern California Feb. 10, 1852 (Othertype 9)
  - 16. A.A. Harwood, appointment. Captain Oct. 2, 1855s. Franklin Pierce, J.C. Dobbin, L.B. Hardin (Othertype 10)
  - 17. Andrew A. Harwood apptmt. Captain July 24, 1856S. [Franklin Pierce], J.C. Dobbin, L.B. Hardin (Othertype 11)
  - 18. A. A. Harwood Apptmt Chief of Bur. of Ordinance and Hydrography in the Dept. of the Navy Aug. 9, 1861s. Abraham Lincoln, Gideon Welles., Wm. Pelloran oversize (Othertype 12)
  - 19. A. A. Harwood apptmt Commodore Feb. 21, 1863s. Abraham Lincoln, Gideon Welles. Wm. P. Moran (Othertype 13)
  - 20. George S. Wilson 1st Lt. Cmmn. 17th Indiana Vols. Apr. 26, 1864s. O.P. Marten, Laz. Noble. glued to mat (Othertype 14)
  - 21. Henry W. Harwood apptmt 3rd Lt. Revenue Service Mar. 7, 1865s. Abraham Lincoln, Geo. Harrington (Othertype 15)
  - 22. Henry W. Harwood apptmt 2nd Lt. Revenue Service June 4, 1866s. Andrew Johnson, Hugh McCulloch (Othertype 16)
  - 23. George S. Wilson apptmt 2nd Lt. 12th Regt. Inf. June 10, 1868s. Andrew Johnson J. M. Schofield, E.D. Townsend (Othertype 17)
  - 24. Andrew A. Harwood apptmt Rear Adm. Returned Feb. 16, 1869s. Andrew Johnson, Gideon Welles, Wm. P. Moran (Othertype 18)
  - 25. Henry W. Harwood apptmt 1st Lt. Revenue Service Apr. 10, 1871s. U.S. Grant, Geo. S.Boutwell (Othertype 19)
  - 26. George S. Wilson apptmt 1st Lt. 12th Inf. Jan. 12, 1877s. U.S. Grant, J.D. Cameron, E. D. Townsend (Othertype 20)
  - 27. Military Order of the Loyal Legion memb. cert. of Geo. S. Wilson Mar. 1, 1885s. [W. S.] Hancock, W.R. Smedberg, John P. Nicholson (Othertype 21)
  - 28. George S. Wilson apptmt Capt. 12th Inf. Aug. 9, 1886,s. Grover Cleveland Wm. C. Endicott, R.C. Drum. (Othertype 22)
  - 29. Geo. S. Wilson apptmt AAG., Major Dec. 12, 1893s. Grover Cleveland, Daniel S. Lamont, Geo. Hughes (Othertype 23)
  - 30. Atlas (26) 1894Pt. XXVI (Othertype 35)
  - 31. Atlas (34) to Accompany the Official Records of the Union and Confederate Armies Wh. G.P.O. 1895Pt. XXIV (Othertype 36)
  - 32. Franklin B. Harwood apptmt 3rd Lt. RCS Aug. 2, 1901s. William McKinley, L.J. Gage (Othertype 24)
  - 33. Franklin B. Harwood apptmt 2nd Lt. Revenue Cutter Service May 3, 1904s. Theodore Roosevelt, L.M. Shaw (Othertype 25)
  - 34. Oakland Tribune Extra Apr. 18, 1906Earthquake (Othertype 32)
  - 35. San Francisco Examiner Nov. 11, 1918(16pp) Germany Surrenders (Othertype 33)
  - 37. Thomas Jefferson engr. portrait and autograph. Engraved by H.B. Hall from an original portrait by G. Stuart. BOX 4 - FRAMED ITEMS
    Transferred to box 3 / folder 31